Elia Bellussi, MBA

Orbassano, Torino ITALY | +39 3336892117 | +44 7775701751

e.bellussi@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/eliabellussi/ | https://github.com/ebellussi

ROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate about technology with 10+ years of experience: working in relationship and project management with stakeholders and clients such as Italian Public Sector, GE Avio Aero (aerospace), Eutelsat - Skylogic (telecommunication), Banca Intesa Sanpaolo (finance) for the complex environment. Specialized in technological innovation, digital transformation, emerging technologies, pre-sale strategy, and open innovation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALMAVIVA — Turin, Italy

June 2020 – Present

Innovation Manager

- Providing intellectual and methodological leadership in projects and proposals, coordinating teams in European calls for tenders, focusing on excellence and impact.
- Contributing to the leadership and growth of the company by bringing fresh and innovative ideas, designing innovation processes, methodologies, and strategies, implementing networks of partners and experts whom the company will be able to activate from day one to manage and deliver diverse projects as well as start-ups' scouting and evaluation.
- Responsible for ideation of customised solutions for public administrations and the national healthcare system, leading their digital transformation with a focus on artificial intelligence, especially about ethics, the internet of things, and blockchain.

SAA – SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT — Turin, Italy

Nov 2020 – Present

Teacher Assistant

- Overseeing case studies analysis for the course in Management Information Systems and Internal Control.
- Guided lectures with practical examples from businesses to clarify how companies manage different issues in their business related the argument of the course.

CONSOFT SISTEMI — Turin, Italy

May 2011 – June 2020

Corporate Business Solutions Manager

- Responsible for the Big Data practice of the company, creating a cross-functional team and developing the business plan.
- Provided courses on NoSQL with a particular focus on MongoDB for bTicino, a subsidiary of Legrand group.
- Trained and tutored a colleague for a project on Big Data Analytics with a Hadoop infrastructure.

Senior System Engineer

- Responsible for projects on continual service development through process design and analytics with a particular focus on KPIs and quality management for GE Avio Aero and Skylogic, a subsidiary of Eutelsat.
- Managed a tailored monitoring system related to the effectiveness of the company's infrastructure of 7.000 servers for Intesa Sanpaolo, as a product owner in an agile team.
- Contributed to the development and management of different projects/B2B products, in collaboration between the enterprise service desk and the enterprise projects development team for GE Avio Aero.

COMAU — Rivalta di Turin, Italy

Feb 2017 – Feb 2017

Guest Lecturer

- Conducting lectures for an Executive Master of Digital Innovation, collaborating with ESCP Business School (Birmingham, UK).
- Training and motivating a group of 30 executive students on coding and its impact on digital transformation.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

CLUB DIRIGENTI INFORMATICI — Turin, Italy

March 2021 – Present

Board of Directors

- Orchestrated events organisation from managing associated resources to executing the strategies.
- Operating guests, sponsors, and partners research, providing analysis and recommendations.
- Explored new partners and interacted with them to create a solid network of stakeholders.

SOCIAL INNOVATION TEAM — Turin, Italy

March 2021 – Present

Startup Mentor

- Reorganised, redesigned, and strengthened the business strategy, product development, and financial statements.
- Coached start-ups' teams to understand customers' needs and wants.

IMPACT HUB — Milan, Italy

Nov 2020 – Present

Startup Mentor

• Mentored and trained teams on design thinking, helping them to develop their business model and strategies.

STARTUP GEEKS — Milan, Italy

Nov 2020 – Present

Startup Mentor

• Supervised teams following the program, providing support and information to be able to complete the assignments.

DIGITAL360 — Milan, Italy

Feb 2020 – Present

Contributing Writer

Authored articles on Design Thinking, Data Strategy, Scenario Planning published in Italian online magazines.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence (MSc)

Expected 2022

Università Degli Studi di Turin — Turin, Italy

Natural Language Processing – Computer Vision – Multi-Agents System – AI Ethics.

Master of Science in Disruptive Innovation (MDI)

Mar 2020

HULT International Business School — San Francisco, USA – GPA: 3.61 with Distinction

Design Thinking – System Thinking – Scenario Planning – Leading Digital Innovation – Co-Creation – Open Innovation.

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

Aug 2019

HULT International Business School — London, UK – GPA: 3.26

Major in Project Management – Minor in Marketing & Sales – Campuses: London, Dubai, and Shanghai.

Bachelor of Computer Science (BSc)

Oct 2011

Università Degli Studi di Turin — Turin, Italy Artificial Intelligence and Multi-Agent System.

Languages

Italian (Native); English (Advanced); Spanish (Basic).

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Work Authorization: EU citizen.

Languages: Italian (native), English (fluent), Spanish (elementary).

Certifications: ITIL V3 Foundation, Foundations in Design Thinking (IDEO), Professional Scrum Master I (Scrum.org). Memberships: IEEE (https://www.ieee.org). Club Dirigenti Informatici (http://www.clubdi.org/). AICA

(http://www.aica.it/)